

JEREMY ESPINOSA

Web Developer

I am a self-driven and highly reliable individual with the ability to work independently or as a team member. A Web Developer with 6 years of experience in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, React JS, Next JS, Node.is, PHP, and mobile responsive web development, as well as excellent skills and abilities in developing clean and efficient code.

Personal Information

Address:

Island Park Paliparan II Dasmarinas City Cavite

Education:

Technological Institute of the Philippines (TIP), Quezon City 2012-2016, BS Computer Science

Contact:

+63 915 979 5830

Email:

jeremyespinosa1995@gmail.com

LinkedIn Account:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremy-espinosa-213236119

Portfolio Link:

https://jeremyespinosa.vercel.app

Work Experiences

March 2023 - Present Manulife

Software Developer

- Responsible for maintaining and improving the current system.
- Works on the different microservice connected to the system.
- Provides support to the current system for enhancing based on user's request.

Technologies:

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- React JS, Redux, Styled Components
- Node JS, Nest JS
- Git, Source Tree

August 2017 - March 2023

Music Tribe

Junior Front End Developer (August 2017 – April 2019) Senior Front End Developer (April 2019 – Present)

- Responsible for creating, improving, and developing websites using the best practices in coding.
- Provides support to current websites to enhance and clean up code for better performance.
- Creates automation project to avoid repetitive task of the company.
- Follows mobile first design and modular coding to have better code structure.
- Leads the front-end developer and set coding standards to follow.

Technologies:

- HTML
- CSS (SCSS), BEM, CSS Module, Mobile First Design
- Bootstrap 3/4/5
- JavaScript (Object Notation Design Pattern), jQuery
- React JS, Next JS, Redux, React Bootstrap, TypeScript, Node JS
- PHP, Codelgniter MVC Framework, MySQL
- JS Task Runner (Gulp, Grunt)
- NPM, NVM
- Git, Source Tree
- Nginx

June 2016 – July 2017

Gee Pacific Services Inc.

Web Developer

- Responsible for ensuring and maintaining the websites.
- Responsible for creating responsive websites for better usage in mobile devices.
- Responsible for utilizing Chinese CMS software in creating websites.

Technologies:

- HTML
- CSS (SCSS), BEM, CSS Module, Mobile First Design
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript, jQuery
- PHP, CodeIgniter MVC Framework, MySQL
- JS Task Runner (Gulp, Grunt)

Projects

Manulife

OTX Wealth System

Software Developer

- Responsible for transforming the mockup into a new client interface.
- Works on different microservice connected to the system.
- Provides support to maintain the current functionality of the system.

Music Tribe

Music Tribe Solutions

Senior Front-End Developer

- Used the Next.js framework to write the client-side code.
- Established coding standards and style guide to follow.
- Code review to maintain the code's quality.
- For faster performance, a CSS module and dynamic import were used.
- Created JSON/API structure to be followed by backend developer.

C2C E-Commerce

Senior Front-End Developer

- Set coding standards for client-side code.
- Code review to maintain the quality of the code.
- Applied mobile first design to make it responsive to different sizes of devices.
- Applied pixel perfect for every page based on the mockup.
- Communicates with vendor to set correct API structure needed in client side.

Sales Forecast

Full Stack Developer

- Authentication using Third Party API.
- Implements Cronjob for importing new data based on scheduled date.
- Can export XLSX file with all the data.
- CRUD data.
- Can track the history who changed the data.
- Dynamic filtering means filter list depends on the current data.

Job Description/Pledge

Full Stack Developer

- Automating job description of the company's employee.
- CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) functionality.
- CRUD functionality varies in user role.
- Exporting of data to CSV file.
- Tracing user action to the application.

Avatar Maker

Full Stack Developer

- Automating the creation of the avatar.
- Creating avatar based on gender, position etc.
- Customizing avatar, you've chosen from top to bottom body parts.
- Storing of avatar, you've created.
- Search functionality to globally search another user created avatar.

Business Card Generator

Full Stack Developer

- Automated the creation of business card of employees.
- · CRUD functionality of the system.
- Sending email to the admin for approving the created business card.
- Admin dashboard for updating the status of those business card created.
- Manage users who can access with admin rights.

Digital Assets Management

Full Stack Developer

- Manages digital assets of the company.
- Search through available assets to avoid duplication.
- Adding/Updating tags/keywords of the assets to search easily.
- Favorites assets to have collection.

Can group download assets and compress it in zip file.

MID Generator

Full Stack Developer

- Automates the creation of the MID.
- · List and filter all MID created by the user.
- Preview on how the PDF will look like when it's converted into a PDF.
- Can generate PDF.
- Can see the previous documents for reference for creating new MID.
- · CRUD functionality of the MID document.

Tannoy, TC Electronic, TC Helicon, Lab Gruppen, Behringer, Midas Website

Front End Developer

- Supporting current and old websites.
- Improving coding structure using Modular Pattern Design.
- Handling data request to updates the downloads, software, and documents of the product.
- Creating new prototype of the current website for better experience for the user.

Gee Pacific Technology Services Inc.

Superants.Inc Website

Front-End Developer

- Created informational websites to know what company offers.
- Used Google Maps API.
- Created contact form to know users' concerns.

Thesis

GeoSCAN

Mobile Developer

- Programmer and concept developer of the application.
- Assigned to acquire data from the Police station of the target location of this app.
- Assigned to utilize the Google Maps API to provide the functionality needed by the application.

Certifications and Awards

- Certificate of Recognition for being on the Dean's List for the First Semester, School Year 2013-2014.
- Certificate of Recognition for being on the Dean's List for the First Semester, School Year 2015-2016.
- Certificate of Recognition for being on the VPAA's List for the Second Semester, School Year 2015-2016
- Certificate of Recognition for winning 3rd place in the Science and Technology Fair 2016 during TIP's 54th Foundation Anniversary